



Diego de Melo Leite

Date of birth: 16/06/1989 | Nationality: Brazilian | Gender: Male | Phone

number: (+351) 965131817 (Mobile) | Email address: diegomelo182@gmail.com

Website: https://www.linkedin.com/in/diegomelo147

Address: Lisbon, Portugal (Home)

About me:

I started my career in 2012 as a Front-end Developer, and in the same year, I started as a full-stack PHP developer with WordPress and Codeigniter. I'm currently assigned as a Tech Lead Developer for a web application and using Jira as the software to create workflows and manage issues. I have been working for various teams with different projects, gaining experience with different technologies like Ruby on Rails, React, and Angular. Mostly related to monitoring projects, application maintenance, and business solutions for Fintechs and Banks. I also have a good team spirit. For more info about me follow my github: https://github.com/diegomelo182

WORK EXPERIENCE

06/2022 - CURRENT Lisbon, Portugal

FRONTEND DEVELOPER KCSIT ALLOCATED AT FARFETCH

At Farfetch, I've worked as a Frontend Developer on a project with an emphasis on AB Testing and Feature Toggle, on my team, I was responsible to develop new features and solve issues using React, Context API, and Redux. Also, as I have knowledge regarding Backend and DevOps (Docker and Rancher) I worked on an initiative that had as a main goal moving from the old Infra solution (AWS EC2-like) to AKS (Kubernetes solution).

Technologies:

- React|S
- Redux
- Context API
- ArgoCD
- Kubernetes

06/2021 - 06/2022 São Paulo, Brazil

TECH LEAD CARGO X

Project with an emphasis in web development using Ruby on Rails for the Logtech (Logistic + Tech) company. The main goal of the company is logistics to deliver products around Brazil since truck drivers registration, companies registration, matches with company and truck driver, documentation emissions, travel mapping, and truck driver monitoring through the mobile app. The architecture was based on microservices systems integrated through web services (Rest API) and AWS SQS, using MVC as a design pattern.

Technologies:

- · Ruby on Rails
- VuelS
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- Postgres
- MicroServices
- SQS | SNS
- Sidekiq
- Rest API

08/2020 - 07/2021 São Paulo-SP, Brazil

FULLSTACK NODEIS DEVELOPER CBYK CONSULTANCY ALLOCATED AT NEW SPACE GROUP

Project with an emphasis in web development using Kraken.JS for the financial company. The client whom I worked for is a giant Brazilian bank called Bradesco, on a B2B product with the bank loans finality. The architecture was based on microservices systems integrated through Webservices (Rest Api), and RabbitMQ | NSQueue queues, using MVC as a design pattern.

Technologies:

- Kraken.JS for Back-end Applications
- ReactJS for SPA Applications
- MongoDB MongoOse and MongoDB
- Micro Frontends Architecture
- Micro Services
- RabbitMQ and NSQueue for async jobs
- Rest API
- Agile Methodologies

11/2019 – 09/2020 São Paulo-SP, Brazil

RUBY DEVELOPER CBYK CONSULTANCY ALLOCATED AT CERC CENTRAL DE RECEBÍVEIS SA

Project with an emphasis in maintenance and web development using Ruby on Rails for the financial company. The goals of the company are credit cards receivables and bank loans. The architecture was based in micro services systems integrated through webservices (Rest Api), using MVC as design pattern.

Technologies:

- Ruby on Rails
- Sidekig and RabbitMQ for async jobs
- Postgres
- |Query
- Micro services
- Rest API

04/2019 - 10/2019 São Paulo-SP, Brazil

RUBY FULLSTACK DEVELOPER PASQUALI SOLUTIONS CONSULTANCY ALLOCATED AT ECOSTAGE

The project at Ecostage was focused on Ruby Full-stack Developer, building custom applications based on geographic information using Geoserver to map interaction and visualization. The architecture was based on Webservices (GraphQL). The main goal of this project was to build applications with an ecological focus, working together with the WWF and Greenpeace to find and map forest fires and show them on a map using the data provided by field agents.

Technologies:

- Ruby on Rails for back-end applications
- ReactJS for SPA applications
- Apollo Client for React
- GraphQL
- Leaflet for fetching and render Geo Server shapes
- GeoServer

04/2018 - 05/2019 São Paulo-SP, Brazil

RUBY DEVELOPER PASQUALI SOLUTIONS CONSULTANCY ALLOCATED AT HUB FINTECH

Project with an emphasis in maintenance and web development using several Ruby frameworks, like Ruby on Rails and Sinatra for the Fintech company. The goals of the company are the production of credit cards, emission of credit cards, and manage credit card transactions. The main goal of the application that I worked with is credit card emissions, in which the client access an admin panel to solicit a credit card to be used for a person who works with our client. The architecture was based in Webservices (Rest Api), using MVC as a design pattern.

Technologies:

- Ruby on Rails and Sinatra for Back-end applications
- SQL Server and Mysql
- Sidekiq and RabbitMQ for async jobs
- Rest APIs
- Agile Methodology (Scrum and Kanban)
- Micro Services

08/2017 - 05/2018 Araraquara-SP, Brazil

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER S2IT

At S2 IT, I have made an app for user sales management, using React Native for hybrid mobile applications, Ruby on Rails Rest Api, and a SPA Angular 8 admin dashboard for database management, yet I worked on a project for a financial company called Rodobens as a Front-end Angular Developer on a car financing product. Also, as an activity the maintenance of legacy systems.

Technologies:

- React Native
- Angular 8
- Ruby on Rails
- Postgres
- Rest API
- Agile Methodology (Kanban and Scrum)

08/2016 - 09/2017 Aracaju-SE, Brazil

PHP/RUBY FULLSTACK DEVELOPER TIRADENTES GROUP

At Tiradentes Group, I worked on Web Development and Management of AWS EC2 and AWS RDS. The websites were to support the students of the university and different areas, however, this time I gave support to all Universities and Colleges that have been part of Tiradentes Group like Facipe, Unit College Center, and São Luis college. The main goal of this project was to develop and maintain websites with an academic focus from Library, academic departments until the entrance exam websites.

Technologies:

- WordPress CMS
- Code Igniter
- Laravel
- Ruby on Rails
- AngularJS and Angular 2+
- MySql
- AWS EC2, AWS RDS, and AWS Route 53

01/2014 - 09/2016 Aracaju-SE, Brazil

PHP/RUBY FULLSTACK DEVELOPER TIRADENTES UNIVERSITY

At Tiradentes, I worked on Web Development and Management of AWS EC2 and AWS RDS. The websites were to support the students of the university and different areas. As an example, I developed a system for the book publisher with Laravel and MySQL. The main goal of this project was to develop and maintain websites with an academic focus from Library, academic departments until the entrance exam websites.

Technologies:

- WordPress CMS
- Code Igniter
- Laravel
- Ruby on Rails
- AngularJS and Angular 2+
- MySql
- AWS EC2, AWS RDS, and AWS Route 53

06/2012 - 02/2014 Aracaju-SE, Brazil

PHP FULLSTACK DEVELOPER TEASER PROPAGANDA

At Teaser Propaganda, I worked with WordPress website development and custom systems using Codeigniter with MySQL. As an advertising company, I worked there on several projects and on various subjects, according to the needs of its clients, from the real state market until the political campaign.

Technologies:

- Code Igniter
- WordPress
- MySql
- JQuery

01/2012 - 07/2012 Aracaju-SE, Brazil

[INTERNSHIP] FRONTEND DEVELOPER TIRADENTES UNIVERSITY

Project with an emphasis in web development using HTML, CSS, and JQuery to build static webpages, and posteriorly it was used in their custom WordPress themes. The main goal of this project was to develop and maintain websites with an academic focus from Library, academic departments until the entrance exam websites.

Technologies:

- HTML
- CSS
- JQuery

DIGITAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

PHP | Ruby | Typescript | Javascript

JS frameworks/Libs

Angular | AngularJS | React | NodeJS | ExpressJS | NestJS | NextJS

Ruby Frameworks

Ruby on Rails | Sinatra

PHP Frameworks

Zend | Laravel | PHP/Code Igniter

Databases

SQL/SQL Server | MySQL | MongoDB | PostgreSQL | Redis

Other Knowledges

SQL | Web (HTML, CSS) | CSS SASS LESS | Git | Linux | Docker | Bootstrap

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

05/2011 - 12/2011 Aracaju-SE, Brazil

WEBDESIGN - TECHNICAL Senac

Address Aracaju-SE, Brazil | Website https://www.se.senac.br/

05/2008 - 12/2012 Aracaju-SE, Brazil

COMPUTING DEGREE Universidade Tiradentes

Address Aracaju-SE, Brazil | Website https://www.unit.br/

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

PUBLICATIONS

Ruby IntelliSense on VS Code with Solargraph - 2021

How to use attr reader, attr writer, and attr accessor on your Ruby Class - 2021

Getting started with React Hooks Context API - 2021

Como eu integrei o Rails 5 API + JWT + Angular - Parte 1 - 2017